In this segment, we'll provide an overview
of the click-through rate prediction pipeline
that you'll be working on in this week's Spark coding lab.
The goal of the lab is to implement a click-through rate
prediction pipeline using various techniques that we've
discussed in this week's lecture.
The raw data consists of a subset of a data
from a Kaggle competition sponsored by Criteo.
This data includes 39 features describing users, ads,
and publishers.
Many of these features contain a large number of categories.
Additionally, for privacy purposes
the features have been anonymized.
We'll be using a small fraction of the Kaggle data.
And the Kaggle data itself is only a small fraction
of Criteo's actual data.
As on the previous lab, you'll split
this data set into training, validation, and test data sets.
You'll next need to extract features
to feed into a supervised learning model.
And feature extraction is the main focus of this lab.
You'll create OHE features, as well as hashed features,
and store these features using a sparse representation.
You will also visualize feature frequency
to get a better sense of the sparsity pattern of this data.
Given a set of features, either OHE or hashed features,
you will use MLlib to train logistic regression models.
You will then perform Hyperparameter
tuning to search for a good regularization parameter,
evaluating the results via log loss,
and visualizing the results of your grid search.
You'll also look at a ROC plot to understand
the trade-off between the false positive
and the true positive rates.
You will then evaluate the final model, again, using log loss
and compare its accuracy to that of a simple baseline that
always predicts the fraction of training points
that correspond to click-through events.
You will also compare the accuracy
of models train using OHE features and hashed features.
The final model you train could be
used for feature click-through rate prediction.